Register of the Petr Berngardovich Struve papers, 1890-1987
Hoover Institution Archives
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1903-1970 (Boxes 3-15)
  - Koshkin, Ivan A., 1943-1944 (Box-folder 7: 70)
  - Kostetskii, Vladimir G., 1927 (Box-folder 7: 71)
  - Kotliarevskii, N., 1926, 1927 (Box-folder 7: 72)
  - Kovalevskii, E., 1927 (Box-folder 7: 73)
  - Kovalevskii, P., 1928 (Box-folder 7: 74)
  - Kozhevnikova, Olga, 1924 (Box-folder 7: 75)
  - Kramarzh, Karel, 1925-1932 (Box-folder 7: 76)
  - Kramarzh, N. N., 1926 (Box-folder 7: 77)
  - Krasnov, P. N., 1926 (Box-folder 7: 78)
  - Krassovska, C., 1920 (Box-folder 7: 79)
  - Kravtsov, N., 1925 (Box-folder 7: 80)
  - Krechetov, Sergei, 1924 (Box-folder 8: 1)
  - Kreze, Leonid A., 1932 (Box-folder 8: 2)
  - Krivoshein, A. V., 1920 (Box-folder 8: 3)
  - Krupenskii, A. N., 1925-1927 (Box-folder 8: 4)
  - Kruzhok Russkoi Natsional'noi Molodezhi, 1927 (Box-folder 8: 5)
  - Krylova, E., 1943 (Box-folder 8: 6)
  - Krym, Solomon S., 1920 (Box-folder 8: 7)
  - Ksiunin, A., 1932 (Box-folder 8: 8)
  - Kudriavtseva, N., 1926 (Box-folder 8: 9)
  - Kulakovskii, S. Iu., 1925 (Box-folder 8: 10)
  - Kul'man, N., 1927, 1943-1944 (Box-folder 8: 11)
  - Kulomzin, A., 1926 (Box-folder 8: 12)
  - Kuprin, A., 1926 (Box-folder 8: 13)
  - Kurch-Ek, E. M., 1927 (Box-folder 8: 14)
  - Kurchinskii, M. A., 1925-1927 (Box-folder 8: 15)
  - Kuskova, E., 1926-1940 (Box-folder 8: 16)
  - Kutepov, General Aleksandr, 1925-1928 (Box-folder 8: 17)
  - Kuz'min-Karavaev, Vladimir D., 1926 (Box-folder 8: 18)
  - Labry, Raoul, 1942 (Box-folder 8: 19)
  - Lampe, General A. A. von, 1925-1927 (Box-folder 8: 20)
  - Landau, Grigorii, 1925-1938 (Box-folder 8: 21)
  - Langer, Joseph, 1927 (Box-folder 8: 22)
  - Lapitskaia, L., 1926 (Box-folder 8: 23)
  - Lappo, I. I., 1925, 1927 (Box-folder 8: 24)
  - Laskarev, V., 1932, 1938, 1943 (Box-folder 8: 25)
  - Lazarevskii, Boris, 1926-1927 (Box-folder 8: 26)
  - Lazarevskii, V. A., 1927 (Box-folder 8: 27)
  - Lbov, M., 1927 (Box-folder 8: 28)
  - Legras, Jules, 1925 (Box-folder 8: 29)
  - Leigh-Smith, P., 1926 (Box-folder 8: 30)
  - Leikhtenbergskii, Duke G. N., 1926-1927 (Box-folder 8: 31)
  - Lemaitre, Henri, 1942 (Box-folder 8: 32)
  - Levin, I., 1925-1926, 1938 (Box-folder 8: 33)
  - Levin, S. I., 1925-1928 (Box-folder 8: 34)
  - Levitskii, V., 1926-1927 (Box-folder 8: 35)
  - Leygues, Georges, 1920 (Box-folder 8: 36)
  - Lingenzevich, Anna, 1926 (Box-folder 8: 37)
  - Lishin, Nikolai, 1925 (Box-folder 8: 38)
  - Litovskii, Georgii, 1927 (Box-folder 8: 39)
  - Liubimova, Liudmila, 1926-1927 (Box-folder 8: 40)
  - Lodyzhenskii, A., undated (Box-folder 8: 41)
  - Lodyzhenskii, Iurii, 1926, 1938 (Box-folder 8: 42)
  - Lomeier, A. E., 1943 (Box-folder 8: 43)
  - Lopatina, Ekaterina M., 1926 (Box-folder 8: 44)
  - Lopukhin, A., 1927 (Box-folder 8: 45)
  - Loshmakov, Aleksei S., 1940 (Box-folder 8: 46)
  - Losskii, N., 1943 (Box-folder 8: 47)
  - Lot, Ferdinand, 1942 (Box-folder 8: 48)
  - Lot-Borodina, Mirra I., 1927, 1943 (Box-folder 8: 49)
  - Lukomskii, General Aleksandr, 1925-1927 (Box-folder 8: 50)
  - Lunts, G., 1920 (Box-folder 8: 51)
  - L'vov, L. I., 1925-1928, 1930, 1932, 1942 (Box-folder 8: 52)
  - L'vov, Nikolai N., 1925-1927 (Box-folder 8: 53)
  - Lysakovskii, A. I., 1927 (Box-folder 8: 54)
  - Lyzlov, Pavel, 1926 (Box-folder 8: 55)
  - Magerovskii, Lev, 1927 (Box-folder 8: 56)
  - Makarov, A., 1927 (Box-folder 8: 57)
  - Makhonine, I. I., 1927 (Box-folder 8: 58)
  - Makhrov, Petr S., 1920 (Box-folder 8: 59)
  - Maklakov, Vasilii A., 1919-1943 (Box-folder 8: 60)
    Includes index of correspondence, typescript and printed copies.
  - Maksimovich, E., 1932-1943 (Box-folder 8: 61)
  - Malinin, V. F., 1925 (Box-folder 8: 62)
  - Mal'tseva, E., undated (Box-folder 8: 63)
  - Marchenko, Mikhail K., 1927 (Box-folder 8: 64)
  - Margulies, Stanislas, 1920 (Box-folder 8: 65)
  - Mariia Fedorovna, Empress Consort of Alexander III, Emperor of Russia, 1926 (Box-folder 8: 66)
  - Marinich, L., 1926 (Box-folder 8: 67)
  - Markov, A., 1931 (Box-folder 8: 68)
  - Markov, Dmitrii, 1926 (Box-folder 8: 69)
  - Matiushkina-Gerke, S., 1926 (Box-folder 8: 70)
  - Mayer, Hans, 1925 (Box-folder 8: 71)
  - Mazon, Andre, 1940-1942 (Box-folder 8: 72)
    Includes typescript copies.
  - Meiendorf, Baron A., 1926 (Box-folder 8: 73)
  - Meier, G. A., 1928 (Box-folder 8: 74)
  - Mel'gunov, Sergei P., 1925-1942 (Box-folder 8: 75)
    Includes typescript and photocopies.
  - Meniker, Leonid, undated (Box-folder 8: 76)
  - Merezhkovskii, D., 1925-1927 (Box-folder 9: 1)
  - Meshcherskaia, Princess V. K., 1927 (Box-folder 9: 2)
  - Metal'nikov, N., 1920 (Box-folder 9: 3)
  - Metal'nikov, S., 1927 (Box-folder 9: 4)
  - Mikhalchev, D., 1926 (Box-folder 9: 5)
  - Military organizations, 1926-1928 (Box-folder 9: 6)
  - Miller, General Evgenii, 1920, 1927 (Box-folder 9: 7)
  - Millerand family, 1943 (Box-folder 9: 8)
  - Mikhel'son, Aleksandr S., 1925 (Box-folder 9: 9)
  - Monkevits, N., 1925 (Box-folder 9: 10)
  - Morsier, E. de, undated (Box-folder 9: 11)
  - Muleshkov, Angel, 1927 (Box-folder 9: 12)
  - Mumm, Olga K., 1937 (Box-folder 9: 13)
  - Munshtein, L., 1926-1927 (Box-folder 9: 14)
  - N., 1926 (Box-folder 9: 15)
  - Nabokov, Konstantin D., 1919 (Box-folder 9: 16)
  - Nazar'eva, E., 1926 (Box-folder 9: 17)
  - Nazhivin, Ivan, 1923 (Box-folder 9: 18)
  - "Negramotnyi rabochii,", undated (Box-folder 9: 19)
  - Neidgart, Dmitrii, 1927 (Box-folder 9: 20)
  - Neander, Boris N., 1925-1926 (Box-folder 9: 21)
  - Nekliudova, V., undated (Box-folder 9: 22)
  - Nelidova, E., 1926 (Box-folder 9: 23)
  - Neratov, Anatolii A., 1920 (Box-folder 9: 24)
  - Nikanorov, I., 1927 (Box-folder 9: 25)
  - Nikiforov, A., 1926 (Box-folder 9: 26)
  - Nikiforov, V., 1932 (Box-folder 9: 27)
  - Nikolaevskii, Boris I., 1925 (Box-folder 9: 28)
  - Nikolai Nikolaevich, Grand Duke, 1926-1927 (Box-folder 9: 29)
  - Nikol'skii, B. A., 1925-1927 (Box-folder 9: 30)
  - Nobel, Emmanuel, 1920 (Box-folder 9: 31)
  - Nol'de, Baroness A. A., 1925 (Box-folder 9: 32)
  - Nol'de, Baron B. E., 1925-1928, 1942-1943 (Box-folder 9: 33)
  - Nol'ken, S., undated (Box-folder 9: 34)
  - Nordman, Maria, 1925 (Box-folder 9: 35)
  - Nordman, N. N., 1925 (Box-folder 9: 36)
  - Novikov, V. N., 1927 (Box-folder 9: 37)
  - Novitskii, Vladimir I., 1920 (Box-folder 9: 38)
  - Novoe Vremia, 1927 (Box-folder 9: 39)
  - Nusinov, E., 1926 (Box-folder 9: 40)
  - Ob"edinenie Slavianskikh Obshchestv v Zagrebe, 1926 (Box-folder 9: 41)
  - Obolenskii, A., 1926-1927 (Box-folder 9: 42)
  - Obolenskii, N., 1926-1928 (Box-folder 9: 43)
  - Obolenskii, V. A., 1943 (Box-folder 9: 44)
  - Obshchestvo "Russkaia Koloniia v Finliandii,", 1927 (Box-folder 9: 45)
  - Okulich, Iosif K., 1926(?) (Box-folder 9: 46)
  - Ol'denburg, S. S., 1925-1928 (Box-folder 9: 47)
  - Ol'denburgskii, Aleskandr, 1926 (Box-folder 9: 48)
  - Olenin, Konstantin, undated (Box-folder 9: 49)
  - Ol'sufiev, D., 1927 (Box-folder 9: 50)
  - Onu, A. M., 1927 (Box-folder 9: 51)
  - Opasenko, Grigorii K., 1927 (Box-folder 9: 52)
  - Optorg Company (Paris), 1920 (Box-folder 9: 53)
  - Orekhov, V. V., 1926 (Box-folder 9: 54)
  - Orlov, G., 1938 (Box-folder 9: 55)
  - Orlov, Mikhail, undated (Box-folder 9: 56)
  - Orlov, Vladimir, 1927 (Box-folder 9: 57)
  - Orlov-Diaborskii, V., 1927 (Box-folder 9: 58)
  - Osobyi Komitet po delam russkikh v Finliandii, 1928 (Box-folder 9: 59)
  - Osorgin, Mikhail M., 1925 (Box-folder 9: 60)
  - Osorgin, Sergei M., 1925 (Box-folder 9: 61)
  - Ostapenko, Aleksei, 1927 (Box-folder 9: 62)
  - Ostrogorskii, G. A., 1931-1943 (Box-folder 9: 63)
  - Ostroukhov, P. A., 1925-1931 (Box-folder 9: 64)
  - Ototskii, M., 1920 (Box-folder 9: 65)
  - Otto, J., 1923 (Box-folder 9: 66)
  - Ovchinnikova, Liudmila, 1926 (Box-folder 9: 67)
  - Paleolog, Sergei N., 1927 (Box-folder 9: 68)
  - Paley, Olga, 1927 (Box-folder 9: 69)
  - Pamfilov, Evgenii, 1928 (Box-folder 9: 70)
  - Panas, Ivan, 1927, 1932 (Box-folder 9: 71)
  - Pares, Sir Bernard, 1927 (Box-folder 9: 72)
  - Pascal, Pierre, 1944 (Box-folder 9: 73)
  - Pasmanik, D. S., 1927 (Box-folder 9: 74)
  - Patentanwalt, 1942 (Box-folder 9: 75)
  - Patzelt, Erna, 1938 (Box-folder 9: 76)
  - Pavlinskii, E., 1926 (Box-folder 9: 77)
  - Pavlov, Ivan P., 1925 (Box-folder 9: 78)
  - Pavlovskii, N., 1926 (Box-folder 9: 79)
  - Peltzer, E. and F., 1938 (Box-folder 9: 80)
  - Peretrukhin, Iosif, 1927 (Box-folder 9: 81)
  - Pergament, Aleksandr, 1925 (Box-folder 9: 82)
  - Persiani, 1926 (Box-folder 9: 83)
  - Pervukhin, M., undated (Box-folder 9: 84)
  - Petrazhitskii, L., 1927 (Box-folder 9: 85)
  - Petrinko, Nikolai, 1926 (Box-folder 9: 86)
  - Petrov, 1926 (Box-folder 9: 87)
  - Petrov, Viktor, 1927 (Box-folder 9: 88)
  - Petrunkevich, A. M., 1927 (Box-folder 9: 89)
  - Piatnitskaia, Sofiia, undated (Box-folder 9: 90)
  - Pierrefitte, Vicomte Jehan Soudan de, 1925 (Box-folder 9: 91)
  - Pilenko, A., 1925-1926 (Box-folder 10: 1)
  - Pinus, Sergei, 1925 (Box-folder 10: 2)
  - Pirang, A., 1927 (Box-folder 10: 3)
  - Pikhno, Petr, 1926 (Box-folder 10: 4)
  - Pliushchevskii-Pliushch, Iu., 1925 (Box-folder 10: 5)
  - Podol'skii, M. N., 1932, 1937 (Box-folder 10: 6)
  - Pogodin, A., 1925 (Box-folder 10: 7)
  - Polezhaeva, N. M., 1925-1927 (Box-folder 10: 8)
  - Poliakov, Iulii F., 1920 (Box-folder 10: 9)
  - Polianskii, V., 1925-1943 (Box-folder 10: 10)
  - Polonskii, Iurii, 1926 (Box-folder 10: 11)
  - Ponafidine, Emma, 1927 (Box-folder 10: 12)
  - Poplavskii, Iulian, 1925 (Box-folder 10: 13)
  - Popova, E., 1926 (Box-folder 10: 14)
  - Popruzhenko, Mikhail, 1927 (Box-folder 10: 15)
  - Pravda (Belgrade), 1927 (Box-folder 10: 16)
  - Pravda (Moscow), 1923 (Box-folder 10: 17)
  - Pravikov, D., undated (Box-folder 10: 18)
  - Pravoslavnyi Bogoslovskii Institut v Parizhe, 1944 (Box-folder 10: 19)
  - Preobrazhenskii, N., 1925-1927 (Box-folder 10: 20)
  - Preobrazhenskii, V., undated (Box-folder 10: 21)
  - Presniakov, V. A., 1925 (Box-folder 10: 22)
  - Protsenko, E., 1926 (Box-folder 10: 23)
  - Pushchina, A., 1924 (Box-folder 10: 24)
  - Pushkarev, S., 1926 (Box-folder 10: 25)
  - R. L. Prager, Buchhandlung und Antiquariat, 1924, 1926 (Box-folder 10: 26)
  - "Rabochie Slantsevogo Rudnika,", 1926 (Box-folder 10: 27)
  - Rakhmaninov, Sergei V., 1927 (Box-folder 10: 28)
  - Rapoport, S., 1925 (Box-folder 10: 29)
  - Rapid-Imprimerie (Paris), 1926-1927 (Box-folder 10: 30)
  - Rataev, Anna and Pavel, 1937-1938 (Box-folder 10: 31)
  - Ratushev, A., 1927 (Box-folder 10: 32)
  - Reitlinger, Iu. N., 1926-1944 (Box-folder 10: 33)
  - Remizov, Aleksei, 1925 (Box-folder 10: 34)
  - Renault, Ernest, 1926 (Box-folder 10: 35)
  - Rennikov, A. M., 1925 (Box-folder 10: 36)
  - Rep'ev, M., 1925-1926 (Box-folder 10: 37)
  - Rep'eva, E., 1926, 1932 (Box-folder 10: 38)
  - Riabushinskii, D. P., 1927 (Box-folder 10: 39)
  - Riabushinskii, V. P., 1925-1928 (Box-folder 10: 40)
  - Rist, Charles, 1942-1943 (Box-folder 10: 41)
  - Rittikh, A. A., 1926 (Box-folder 10: 42)
    Includes clipping from Times (London), "The Russians in Exile," 1926.
  - Rodichev, G., undated (Box-folder 10: 43)
  - Rodicheva, A. F., 1930 (Box-folder 10: 44)
  - Rodionov, Ivan, 1926 (Box-folder 10: 45)
  - Rodionov, Nikolai, 1926 (Box-folder 10: 46)
  - Rosenstein, P. N., 1925 (Box-folder 10: 47)
  - Rossiiskoe Tsentral'noe Ob'edinenie, 1926-1927 (Box-folder 10: 48)
  - Rostovtsev, M. I., 1920, 1925, 1927 (Box-folder 10: 49)
  - Rovbe, undated (Box-folder 10: 50)
  - Rudanovskaia, E., undated (Box-folder 10: 51)
  - Rumanov, A., 1927 (Box-folder 10: 52)
  - Russian Economic Association in London, 1920 (Box-folder 10: 53)
  - Russkii Institut Sel'skokhoziaistvennoi Kooperatsii v Prage, 1925 (Box-folder 10: 54)
  - Russkoe Kul'turno-Prosvetitel'noe Obshchestvo Im. Al. Dukhnovicha, 1927 (Box-folder 10: 55)
  - Russkii Natsional'nyi Komitet, undated (Box-folder 10: 56)
  - Rybakov, Colonel Nikolai, 1927 (Box-folder 10: 57)
  - Rybinskii, Nikolai Z., 1931-1932 (Box-folder 10: 58)
  - Ryss, P. Ia., 1927, 1944 (Box-folder 10: 59)
  - Sabatier, A., 1943 (Box-folder 10: 60)
  - Sablin, E., 1920, 1925-1928, 1938 (Box-folder 10: 61)
  - Sadovskii, Iakov D., 1925 (Box-folder 10: 62)
  - Sakhanev, Vsevolod, 1925 (Box-folder 10: 63)
  - Sakhnovskii, Grigorii G., 1926 (Box-folder 10: 64)
  - Saltykov, Count N., 1925 (Box-folder 10: 65)
  - Samokhvalov, N., 1927 (Box-folder 10: 66)
  - Samsonova, V. M., 1925-1928, 1931 (Box-folder 10: 67)
  - Sanatorium "Les Pins,", 1927 (Box-folder 10: 68)
  - Savchenko, I., 1925 (Box-folder 10: 69)
  - Savich, Ivan, 1925 (Box-folder 10: 70)
  - Savich, N. V., undated (Box-folder 10: 71)
  - Savin, N., 1925 (Box-folder 10: 72)
  - Savinkov, B. V., 1920 (Box-folder 10: 73)
  - Sazonova, Anna, 1923-1928, 1932, 1938 (Box-folder 10: 74)
  - Seligman, Edwin, 1927-1929 (Box-folder 10: 75)
  - Semenov, Iu. F., 1926(?), 1946(?) (Box-folder 10: 76)
  - Semenov, N., 1925 (Box-folder 10: 77)
  - Semenov, V., 1925 (Box-folder 10: 78)
  - Semenov-Tian-Shansky, V. P., 1927 (Box-folder 10: 79)
  - Seraphim, Archbishop, undated (Box-folder 10: 80)
  - Serafim, N. J., 1925-1926 (Box-folder 10: 81)
  - Serbian National Bank, undated (Box-folder 10: 82)
  - Serebrennikov, Vladimir, 1927 (Box-folder 10: 83)
  - Sergei, Bishop, 1938-1939 (Box-folder 10: 84)
  - Sergievskoe Podvorie, Paris, 1927-1928 (Box-folder 10: 85)
  - Shakhmatov, M. V., 1925-1927, 1938 (Box-folder 10: 86)
  - Sharshikov, M., 1926 (Box-folder 10: 87)
  - Shastin, I., 1927 (Box-folder 11: 1)
  - Shatilov, P. N., 1928 (Box-folder 11: 2)
  - Shcherbachev, General, 1920 (Box-folder 11: 3)
  - Shcherbatov, Prince N., 1925-1927 (Box-folder 11: 4)
  - Shchukina, Sofiia, 1926 (Box-folder 11: 5)
  - Shebek, E., 1926 (Box-folder 11: 6)
  - Shebor, Iosif, 1927 (Box-folder 11: 7)
  - Shevich, M. K., 1926-1927 (Box-folder 11: 8)
  - Shidlovskii, I. I., 1926 (Box-folder 11: 9)
  - Shinkarenko, Major-General Nikolai, undated (Box-folder 11: 10)
  - Shirinskii-Shikhmatov, Iurii, 1926 (Box-folder 11: 11)
  - Shlinkevich, S., 1926 (Box-folder 11: 12)
  - Shmelev, Ivan, 1925-1935, 1939 (Box-folder 11: 13)
  - Shmemann, Andrei, 1927 (Box-folder 11: 14)
  - Shmidt, N., undated (Box-folder 11: 15)
  - Shmurlo, Evgenii V., 1920 (Box-folder 11: 16)
  - Shplet, Dimitrii, 1926 (Box-folder 11: 17)
  - Shtern, S. F., 1926-1943 (Box-folder 11: 18)
  - Shtrandtman, V. N., 1937 (Box-folder 11: 19)
  - Shul'gin V. V., 1925-1928 (Box-folder 11: 20)
  - Shul'gina, E., 1928 (Box-folder 11: 21)
  - Sil'verstran, Boris P., 1928 (Box-folder 11: 22)
  - Simmel, G., 1926 (Box-folder 11: 23)
  - Sipiagina, Aleksandra, 1926 (Box-folder 11: 24)
  - Skalon, G., 1925 (Box-folder 11: 25)
  - Skalon, M. N., 1925-1926 (Box-folder 11: 26)
  - Sliosberg, H., 1925 (Box-folder 11: 27)
  - Société Maritime et Commerciale de France (Paris), 1920 (Box-folder 11: 28)
  - Soiuz Russkikh Literatorov v Parizhe, 1928 (Box-folder 11: 29)
  - Soiuz Russkikh Pisatelei v Iugoslavii, 1932 (Box-folder 11: 30)
  - Sokolov, B., 1920, 1925 (Box-folder 11: 31)
  - Sokolovskii, 1927 (Box-folder 11: 32)
  - Sokol'skii, M. and V., 1936-1937 (Box-folder 11: 33)
  - Sokol'tsev, D., 1926 (Box-folder 11: 34)
  - Solov'ev, A., 1931 (Box-folder 11: 35)
  - Soltykov, Count Aleksandr, 1925 (Box-folder 11: 36)
  - Sorbiers de la Tourrasse, 1920 (Box-folder 11: 37)
  - Sorokin, Pitirim, 1925-1927 (Box-folder 11: 38)
  - Spasskii, A., 1928 (Box-folder 11: 39)
  - Spektorskii, E. V., 1925, 1927-1929, 1932, 1937-1938 (Box-folder 11: 40)
  - Springer Verlag, 1932 (Box-folder 11: 41)
  - "St.,", 1926 (Box-folder 11: 42)
  - Stael, Baron, 1926 (Box-folder 11: 43)
  - Stakhovich, A. A., 1943 (Box-folder 11: 44)
  - Stark, A., 1927 (Box-folder 11: 45)
  - Starynkevich, K., 1925 (Box-folder 11: 46)
  - Stefanovskii, S. M., 1943-1944 (Box-folder 11: 47)
  - Stepanova, Viktoriia, undated (Box-folder 11: 48)
  - Stiller, G., 1925-1926 (Box-folder 11: 49)
  - Stol'ts, Liubov', 1927 (Box-folder 11: 50)
  - Stolypin, Arkadii P., 1927 (Box-folder 11: 51)
  - Strakhovskii, Leonid, 1925 (Box-folder 11: 52)
  - Stroev, V. N., 1925 (Box-folder 11: 53)
  - Struve, Aleksei
    - 1921-1943 (Box-folder 11: 54)
    - Typescript copies, 1942-1943 (Box-folder 11: 55)
  - Struve, Arkadii
    - 1925-1931 (Box-folder 11: 56)
    - 1932 (Box-folder 11: 57)
    - 1933 (Box-folder 11: 58)
    - 1942-1943 (Box-folder 11: 59)
  - Struve, G., 1926 (Box-folder 12: 1)
  - Struve, Gleb
    - 1922-1929 (Box-folder 12: 2)
    - 1930 (Box-folder 12: 3)
    - 1931 (Box-folder 12: 4)
    - 1932-1933 (Box-folder 12: 5)
    - 1934-1936 (Box-folder 12: 6)
    - 1937-1938 (Box-folder 12: 7)
    - 1939 (Box-folder 12: 8)
    - 1940-1941 (Box-folder 12: 9)
    - Typescript copies
      - 1932-1937 (Box-folder 12: 10)
      - 1938-1941 (Box-folder 12: 11)
  - Struve, Nina
    - 1925 (Box-folder 13: 1)
    - 1926 (Box-folder 13: 2-5)
    - 1927 (Box-folder 13: 6)
    - 1928 (Box-folder 13: 7)
    - 1929 (Box-folder 13: 8)
    - 1931 (Box-folder 13: 9)
    - 1932 (Box-folder 13: 10)
    - 1933 (Box-folder 14: 1)
    - 1937 (Box-folder 14: 2)
    - 1938-1940 (Box-folder 14: 3)
  - Struve, O., 1926 (Box-folder 14: 4)
    Includes clippings re National Congress of 1926, Chicago Daily Tribune.
  - Struve, P., 1942 (Box-folder 14: 5)
  - Struve, Vadim, 1919 (Box-folder 14: 6)
  - Struve-Florovskii-Novgorodtsev family, 1925 (Box-folder 14: 7)
  - Student organizations, 1925-1927 (Box-folder 14: 8)
  - Stupnitskii, A., 1943 (Box-folder 14: 9)
  - Sukhotin, Lev M. and E., 1925, 1938, 1942-1944 (Box-folder 14: 10)
  - Sukhotina-Tolstaia, T., 1927 (Box-folder 14: 11)
  - Surguchev, I., 1927 (Box-folder 14: 12)
  - Svoimi Putiami, 1925 (Box-folder 14: 13)
  - Sychov, General K., 1926 (Box-folder 14: 14)
  - Switzerland. Département de Justice et de Police, Berne, 1938 (Box-folder 14: 15)
  - Tagantsev, N., 1942-1943 (Box-folder 14: 16)
  - Taranovskii, F. V., 1931 (Box-folder 14: 17)
  - Tatishchev, B. A., 1920, 1926-1927 (Box-folder 14: 18)
  - Tatishcheva, B., undated (Box-folder 14: 19)
  - Taube, M. A., 1927 (Box-folder 14: 20)
  - Teffi, Nadezhda, 1926 (Box-folder 14: 21)
  - Tenisov, I., 1927 (Box-folder 14: 22)
  - Tereshchenko, M. I., 1927 (Box-folder 14: 23)
  - Tilliard, Iu., 1926 (Box-folder 14: 24)
  - Titov, F. I., 1927 (Box-folder 14: 25)
  - Tiutchev, I., 1927 (Box-folder 14: 26)
  - Tkhorzhevskii, Ivan, 1928 (Box-folder 14: 27)
  - Tolstaia-Miloslavskaia, E., 1927 (Box-folder 14: 28)
  - Trakhterev, O. S., 1928 (Box-folder 14: 29)
  - Trepov, A., 1925-1926 (Box-folder 14: 30)
  - Tret'iakov, S. N., 1920, 1926-1928 (Box-folder 14: 31)
  - Troitskii, S. V., 1937 (Box-folder 14: 32)
  - Trubetskaia, Princess M., 1942 (Box-folder 14: 33)
  - Trubetskaia, Princess V. N., 1943 (Box-folder 14: 34)
  - Trubetskoi, Prince A. E., 1943 (Box-folder 14: 35)
  - Trubetskoi, Prince G. N.
    - 1926-1928 (Box-folder 14: 36)
    - Photocopies of above (Box-folder 14: 37)
  - Trubetskoi, Prince S. E., 1925-1928 (Box-folder 14: 38)
  - Tsankov, A., 1925 (Box-folder 14: 39)
  - Tsurikov, N. A.
    - 1925-1927 (Box-folder 14: 40)
    - 1927 (Box-folder 14: 41)
    - 1928-1943 (Box-folder 14: 42)
    - Typescript copies, 1935-1943 (Box-folder 15: 1)
    - Comments of Nikolai Tsurikov re his correspondence with Petr Struve (Box-folder 15: 2)
  - Tuneev, D., 1926 (Box-folder 15: 3)
  - Tyrkova-Williams, Ariadna, holograph, photocopies, and typescripts, 1919-1926 (Box-folder 15: 4)
  - Vakhrushev, Petr Ia., 1926 (Box-folder 15: 5)
  - Valentinov-Lange, A. A., 1927 (Box-folder 15: 6)
  - Valisovskii, T., 1925 (Box-folder 15: 7)
  - Varshavskii, S. I., 1925-1928 (Box-folder 15: 8)
  - Vasil'chikov, I., undated (Box-folder 15: 9)
  - Verhovskoy, Sergei, 1927 (Box-folder 15: 10)
  - Vernadskii, V., 1925 (Box-folder 15: 11)
  - Veselkina, E., undated (Box-folder 15: 12)
  - Vilinskii, S. G., 1927 (Box-folder 15: 13)
  - Vilkov, A., 1927, 1937 (Box-folder 15: 14)
  - Vinogradov, N. N., 1925, 1927 (Box-folder 15: 15)
  - Vinogradov, Pavel, 1925 (Box-folder 15: 16)
  - Vipper, Robert, 1925 (Box-folder 15: 17)
  - Vistoft, A., 1926 (Box-folder 15: 18)
  - Vitalii, Archbishop, 1938 (Box-folder 15: 19)
  - Vitt, A., 1938 (Box-folder 15: 20)
  - Vlasov, I., 1927 (Box-folder 15: 21)
  - Vodov, S., 1925 (Box-folder 15: 22)
  - Voetskii, S., 1926 (Box-folder 15: 23)
  - Voitsekhovskii, Iurii, 1926 (Box-folder 15: 24)
  - Volens, N., 1923-1927 (Box-folder 15: 25)
  - Volkonskaia, Princess Sofiia, 1927-1928 (Box-folder 15: 26)
  - Volkonskii, Prince Aleksandr M., 1926-1927 (Box-folder 15: 27)
  - Volkonskii, Prince Vladimir, 1925 (Box-folder 15: 28)
  - Vondrak, V., 1927 (Box-folder 15: 29)
  - Vonjarjarsay(?), V., 1926 (Box-folder 15: 30)
  - Voronin, S., 1925 (Box-folder 15: 31)
  - Vrangel', Baroness Mariia, 1928 (Box-folder 15: 32)
  - Vrangel', N., 1920 (Box-folder 15: 33)
  - Vrangel', General Baron Petr, 1920-1921, 1927 (Box-folder 15: 34)
  - Weissenberger, Georg, 1942 (Box-folder 15: 35)
  - Whittemore, 1920 (Box-folder 15: 36)
  - Williams, Harold, 1925-1926 (Box-folder 15: 37)
  - Zaitsev, A., 1926 (Box-folder 15: 38)
  - Zaitsev, K.
    - 1925-1928 (Box-folder 15: 39)
    - Correspondence related to his work as editor of Vozrozhdenie, 1925-1928 (Box-folder 15: 40)
  - Zak, A., 1927 (Box-folder 15: 41)
  - Zander, L. A., 1927 (Box-folder 15: 42)
  - Zapevalov, S., 1927 (Box-folder 15: 43)
  - Zavadskaia, N., 1926 (Box-folder 15: 44)
  - Zavadskii, Sergei, 1928 (Box-folder 15: 45)
  - Zavalov, P., 1927 (Box-folder 15: 46)
  - Zdzekhovskii, Marian, 1931 (Box-folder 15: 47)
  - Zen'kovskii, A., 1925 (Box-folder 15: 48)
  - Zen'kovskii, V., 1926 (Box-folder 15: 49)
  - Zernin, A., 1926 (Box-folder 15: 50)
  - Zernov, M., 1927 (Box-folder 15: 51)
  - Zernov, N. M., 1927 (Box-folder 15: 52)
  - Zhekulin, N. S., 1925 (Box-folder 15: 53)
  - Zhebunov, S., 1926 (Box-folder 15: 54)
  - Zhitovskaia, Vera L., 1926 (Box-folder 15: 55)
  - Zhukovskii, S., 1920 (Box-folder 15: 56)
  - Zile, R., 1938 (Box-folder 15: 57)
  - Zivnostenska Banka v Praze, 1927 (Box-folder 15: 58)
  - Zvorykin, Nikolai N., 1928 (Box-folder 15: 59)
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 1903-1981 (Boxes 16-24)
  Notes, drafts, typescript and printed copies of books, articles, lectures, and book reviews by Petr Struve, arranged chronologically. Includes clippings of his newspaper articles.
  - Osvobozhdenie
    - No. 20/21, 1903 (Box-folder 16: 1)
    - No. 18(42), 1904 (Box-folder 16: 2)
  - Birzhevye Vedomosti and Rech', clippings, 1914 (Box-folder 16: 3)
  - Russkaia Svoboda, tearsheets
    - "Nasha zadacha," No. 1, 1917 (Box-folder 16: 4)
    - "Bez annaksii i kontributsii," No. 7, 1917 (Box-folder 16: 5)
    - "Illiuzii russkikh sotsialistov," No. 7, 1917 (Box-folder 16: 6)
    - "Neskol'ko slov o "Lige russkoi kul'tury," No. 9, 1917 (Box-folder 16: 7)
  - Russkaia Mysl', printed copies
    Only lead article is listed; clipping may include more than one article.
    - "Proshloe, nastoiashchee, budushchee,", undated (Box-folder 16: 8)
    - "Vladimir Galaktionovich Korolenko,", undated (Box-folder 16: 9)
    - "Oshibki i sofizmy 'istoricheskago' vzgliada na revoliutsiiu,", undated (Box-folder 16: 10)
    - "Rossiia,", 1920 (Box-folder 16: 11)
    - "Aksakovy i Aksakov,", 1923 (Box-folder 16: 12)
  - Rul', photocopies of miscellaneous printed articles, 1924-1926 (Box-folder 16: 13)
  - Segodnia
    - Answers to a questionnaire on the 10th anniversary of the Russian Revolution, typescript copy, 1927 (Box-folder 16: 14)
    - "Karl Marks i sud'by marksizma," printed copy, 1934 (Box-folder 16: 15)
  - Vozrozhdenie, printed copies
    - "Dnevnik politika," "Eshche o tserkovnom spore,", 1927 February (Box-folder 16: 16)
    - "Zametki pisatelia"
      - "Russkii iazyk--ochistiteli i zasoriteli,", 1926 April (Box-folder 16: 17)
      - "Konstantin Leont'ev,", 1926 May (Box-folder 16: 18)
      - "O pustoutrobii i ozorstve,", 1926 June (Box-folder 16: 19)